A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development, International Training and Research, Office Files of John Howard FA608
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development, International Training and Research, Office Files of John Howard
1951-1969, bulk 1951-1966
1951-1966
Rockefeller Archive Center
Howard, John A.
Ford Foundation
FA608
30.13 Cubic Feet 23 record storage boxes
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Loosely Alphabetical. Collection consists of 1 series.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Subject Files, 1951-1969, bulk 1951-1966
Biographical / Historical
John Howard was Director of the Ford Foundation's International Training and Research Program (ITR) from 1954 to 1966. Prior to joining the Foundation in 1951, Howard had a number of different assignments with the United States State Department. These positions included Special Assistant to the Secretary of State, Dean Acheson, and deputy chief for the American Mission to Greece. Howard earned a Ph.D. in physical chemistry from Harvard University and a law degree from the University of Chicago. He died in 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Contains subject files.
- Subject Files, 1951-1969, bulk 1951-1966; 1951-1966; I
  - A -- General (folder 1), 1951-1961 (Box 1)
  - A -- General (folder 2), 1960-1965 (Box 1)
  - A -- General (folder 3), 1961-1966 (Box 1)
  - Afghanistan -- General Correspondence, 1952-1966 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- William O. Brown -- Consultant, 1952-1956 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- William O. Brown -- Consultant -- Mel Fox Files, 1955-1965 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- William O. Brown -- Trip to Africa, 1953 -- Reports (African Training and Research File -- Lamb) (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Career Opportunities for African Specialists -- M.J. Fox -- African Studies Association Meeting (September 1959), 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Commission for Technical Cooperation in Africa South of the Sahara (CCTA), 1961 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Conferences with State Department Re: Africa and General Correspondence, 1952-1959 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Conferences -- Princeton University Conference on Africa, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Conferences -- Greenbrier Conference on Africa Sponsored by the Carnegie Corporation (May 1958) (folder 1), 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Conferences -- Greenbrier Conference on Africa Sponsored by the Carnegie Corporation (May 1958) (folder 2), 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Conferences -- International Congress of Africanists -- Ibadan (September 9-11, 1961), 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Conferences -- U.S. National Commission for UNESCO -- 8th National Conference on Africa and the United States (October 22-26, 1961), 1961 October 22-26 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Conferences -- Conference on Federalization in Africa, 1962 February 12-17 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Docket Items Re: Activities in Africa, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Educational Exchange with Africa -- Memorandum/Program Recommendation by M.J. Fox, 1960 September 2 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Educational Exchange with Africa -- M.J. Fox -- Materials, 1954-1961 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Educational Exchange, 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Educational Exchange -- State Department Exchange Program, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- Educational Services, Inc. -- African Summer Study -- MIT Draft of General Report, 1961 September 1 (Box 1)
  - Africa -- "Faces of Africa" (L9-883), 1959 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- "Faces of Africa" (National Educational Television and Radio Center), 1959 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Background Papers Re: Mission, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Conference on African Administration -- Cambridge, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Discussion with Experts, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- John Howard Notes, Miscellaneous Work Sheets, circa 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Correspondence with Team (incl. photographs), 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Interim Correspondence with Howard, Fox, Brown, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Ford Foundation Internal Papers and Correspondence Re: Mission, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Itineraries Prepared by Host Countries, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Itinerary, Visas, etc., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- "Leaders in Nigeria" and "Leaders in the Gold Coast" Reports by Betty George, 1956-1958 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Miscellaneous (Recommendations, Reports, Biographies, etc.), 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Melvin J. Fox -- Index of Contacts, undated (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Official Communications with African Leaders, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- People to See in Africa, circa 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Ruth Sloan Report on Missions, 1955-1959 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Team Reports from Africa, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- First Mission to Africa (ITR) -- Visit to Ford Foundation Fellows in Africa, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1956 April-June (Box 2)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1956 July-September (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1956 October-December (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1957 January-March (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1957 April-June (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1957 July-September (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1957 October-December (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence (folder 1), 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence (folder 2), 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- General Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Georgetown University -- African Languages Proposal, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Joint ITR/OD Approach to Development of Policy on Educational Interchange, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Memoranda, 1952-1955 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Memoranda, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Memoranda, 1960-1963 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Operation Crossroads Africa -- Proposed May 1960 Docket Item, 1959-1963 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Publications, Documents, Background Material, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Report on Africa and Supplement to Report on African Studies -- M.J. Fox, 1961 April 4 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Survey of African Research and Training in the U.S. (DeKiewiet, Fallers, Cowan, Rosberg group), 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Trip to Africa (Melvin J. Fox) -- African Language Training Project and "Trip to the Union of South Africa" Report -- Charles Ferguson, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- Undergraduate Scholarship Program for African Students and General Re-Collaborating Colleges Scheme -- African-American Institute, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Africa -- West African Languages Survey -- Professor Joseph Greenberg, Columbia University -- OD Grant (PA60-115), 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - African Scholarship Program of American Universities -- Expenses -- McHenry Study Team Meetings, 1962 May 1; May 7, 1962 (Box 3)
  - African Scholarship Program of American Universities -- McHenry Team Study, 1961-1962 May (Box 3)
  - African Scholarship Program of American Universities -- McHenry Team Study -- Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Agency for International Development, 1962-1965 (Box 3)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities -- Meeting, Washington (November 14, 1960) -- "Foreign Technical Cooperation Committee" (Box 3)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities -- Centennial Meeting, Kansas City, Missouri (November 12-16, 1961), 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - American Association of Universities and International Association of Universities, 1958-1962 (Box 3)
  - American Council of Learned Societies -- Area and Language Specialists, 1952-1954 (Box 3)
  - American Council of Learned Societies -- General File, 1955-1966 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education -- General, 1956-1962 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education -- Commission on Education and International Affairs -- General File, 1956-1962 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education -- Language and Area Centers -- Correspondence Re: NDEA Report, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee -- Summer 1961, 1959-1961 (Box 4)
  - American Political Science Association -- Meetings in Washington, D.C. (September 10-12, 1959) (Box 4)
  - American University -- General, 1956-1962 (Box 4)
  - American University Field Services -- General, 1955-1965 (Box 4)
  - Arias, Dr. Julio Rodriguez (Buenos Aires) -- Institute for Latin American Integration, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Asia -- Asia and the Near East -- Conference on Land Tenure, New York (December 8-9, 1952), 1952-1953 (Box 4)
  - Asia -- Asian Studies -- General, 1957-1961 (Box 4)
  - Asia -- Conference on American Research in Asia held in New York (May 11, 1957), 1957 May 11 (Box 4)
  - Asia -- International Cooperation in Development of Asian Countries (Ben Moore - Ed Mason) -- Report, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
  - Asia -- National Council on Asian Affairs -- Elinor Wolf, John Melby, et al. (L5-160), 1955-1959 (Box 4)
  - Asia -- Staff Conference on Training and Research in Southeast Asian Affairs, 1954 March 5 (Box 4)
  - Association Internationale des Etudiants en Sciences Economiques et Commerciales (L9-525), 1960 (Box 4)
  - Association of Universities of British Commonwealth -- University of Toronto, 1958-1961 (Box 4)
  - Australian Universities, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - B -- General Files (folder 1), 1952-1966 (Box 4)
  - B -- General Files (folder 2), 1958-1963 (Box 4)
  - British Columbia, University of, 1956-1960 (Box 4)
  - British Universities -- Principals Conference, Inter-University Council for Higher Education Overseas -- Carnegie Corporation -- Gould House, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Brookings Institution -- General Files, 1958-1965 (Box 4)
  - Brookings Institution -- Program of Studies of U.S. Relations with Developing Countries, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Brookings Institutions -- Proposed Long-Term Support (L65-54, non-program), 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Brookings Institutions -- Proposed Long-Term Support (attachments), 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Brookings Institution -- Re: Study of Political Role of Labor in the Underdeveloped Countries (H. Field Havilland), 1960 (Box 4)
  - Burma, 1956-1961 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- Agricultural Institute, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- Burma Technical Institute (Dunwoody Institute), 1954 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- Council on Foreign Relations Study Group on Burma and the U.S., 1958 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- General Correspondence, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- General Correspondence, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- General Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- General Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
  - Burma (office) -- General Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Burma (office) -- General Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- Grant Requests, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- Mass Education Council Program, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- New York University -- Frank Trager, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- Pali University -- Education Center for Oriental Studies, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Burma -- State Scholarship Program, 1955 (Box 5)
  - C -- General Files, 1957-1963 (Box 5)
  - California, University of -- Berkeley -- Center of Slavic and East European Studies, 1957-1960 (Box 5)
  - California, University of -- General, 1957-1964 (Box 5)
  - Carnegie Corporation -- General File, 1960-1963 (Box 5)
  - Chicago, University of -- General, 1957-1963 (Box 5)
  - Chicago, University of -- Institute of Contemporary Thought in the United States -- Dean Strozier, 1956-1957 (Box 5)
  - China -- ACITR Discussions on China, 1955-1960 (Box 6)
  - China -- Conference on Advanced Chinese Language Training, 1955 March 19 (Box 6)
  - China -- Education, 1960-1966 (Box 6)
  - China -- Everton-Barnett Memoranda, 1961 (Box 6)
  - China -- Exchange Fellowships, 1956-1960 (Box 6)
  - China -- Langer, Paul F. re: Board of Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) Survey, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - China -- Langer, Paul F. -- Consultancy, 1955 (Box 6)
  - China -- Non-Governmental Organizations Interested in Asian Affairs, 1954 (Box 6)
  - China -- Organizations Concerned with Far Eastern Studies and Asia Education, 1954-1955 (Box 6)
  - China -- Reaction of Generalists to China Program, 1954 (Box 6)
  - China -- Special China Fellowships, 1960-1961 (Box 6)
  - China -- Taiwan Center, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - China -- Training of Chinese, Chinese Prisoners of War, Overseas Chinese, Chinese Colleges, 1954 (Box 6)
  - China -- Training Problems (disciplinary, language, etc.), 1958 (Box 6)
  - Citizen Education in World Affairs -- Foundation Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - (The) College and World Affairs, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - (The) College and World Affairs, 1962 (Box 6)
  - (The) College and World Affairs, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Columbia University -- Council for Atomic Age Studies, 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - A -- General Files, 1959-1962 (Box 7)
  - Akrawi, Dr. Matta -- UNESCO, 1960-1964 (Box 7)
  - American Council on Education, 1960-1962 (Box 7)
  - Bibliographic Materials -- General, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Brickman, William H., 1952-1961 (Box 7)
  - Butts, R. Freeman, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Foundation for Advancement of Teaching -- Digest of Discussion on Basic Issue, 1959 November 18 (Box 7)
  - Commager, Henry Steele -- Address Re: The University and the Community, 1959 May 12 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Educational Interchange Policy, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Coombs, Philip -- CUWA Project -- Special File on Philip Coombs and Newly Created Branch of State Department for Educational and Cultural Affairs (CU), 1960-1964 (Box 7)
  - Council on International Cooperation in Education -- Memorandum (revised) -- Outline of Council, 1960 April 18 (Box 7)
  - Committee on the University and World Affairs (CUWA) -- Country Studies, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Cowley, W.H. and CUWA, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - Education and World Affairs -- Overseas Development (OD) Funds -- Support of the Overseas Educational Service, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Education and World Affairs -- FAP on CUWA Project -- Special Folder on "Papers on Continuing Agency", 1956-1961 (Box 7)
  - Education and World Affairs -- General Support -- Six Years Beginning Oct 1, 1966 -- $3 Million (PA63-347 A) (folder 1), 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Education and World Affairs -- General Support -- Six Years Beginning Oct 1, 1966 -- $3 Million (PA63-347 A) (folder 2), 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Education and World Affairs -- General Support -- $2 Million, 1963-1965 (Box 7)
  - Elliott, William Y., 1960 (Box 7)
  - F -- General Files, 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Students -- General File, 1958-1962 (Box 8)
  - Fulbright, Senator J.W., 1960 (Box 8)
  - Fulbright, Senator J.W. -- Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - G -- General Files -- Reports, Correspondence Re: Education, 1958-1960 (Box 8)
  - Gardner, John -- Re: Higher Education and the Government, University and World Affairs -- Reports, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - H -- General Files Re: Education and Universities, 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - Hannah, Harold W. -- The Advancement of Education in Nigeria and the United States, 1960 May (Box 8)
  - Harvard University -- General, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Harvard University -- Letter to President Pusey from Dean Bundy, 1959 November 16 (Box 8)
  - Health, Education and Welfare -- U.S. Office of Education -- General, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - I -- General Files, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Ike, Nobutaka -- American Cooperation with Japanese Universities -- Report, 1960 April (Box 8)
  - India -- General, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - Institute of International Education -- Agreement between IIE and ACE on Related Activities of the American Council on Education and IIE, 1956 May 22 (Box 8)
  - International Association of Universities -- Roger Keyes -- General, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - International Cooperation Administration (ICA) -- General, 1960 (Box 8)
  - ICA -- Proposed Outline for the Study of Technical Assistance to Less Developed Countries -- Jack Ohly, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - ICA -- Ralph Ruffner, Director of Office of Educational Services, 1960 January (Box 8)
  - J -- General Files Incl. Ronald Jones "Personnel Management for Technical Cooperation", 1959 (Box 8)
  - K -- General Files, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - L -- General Files, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - Lewis, L.J. and Karl W. Bigelow -- Cooperation between British and American Universities, 1960 May (Box 8)
  - MIT -- Exceprts from the Study of the Center for International Studies at MIT for the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Medlin, W.K. -- Soviet Education in World Affairs -- Report, 1960 May (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Discussion Paper for Meeting on August 15, 1959 in Washington, D.C., 1959 July 30 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Summary of Meeting on August 15, 1959, 1959 August-September (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Letter from John Howard to CUWA incl. Summary of Discussion at August 15, 1959 Meeting, 1959 September 1 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Plan of Study Re: CUWA for October 9, 1959 Meeting, 1959 September 28 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Summary of Meeting on October 9, 1959, 1959 October 16 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Outline of Report for CUWA for December 29-30, 1959 Meeting in Princeton, 1959 November 10 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Staff Note (CUWA) for December 29-30, 1959 Meeting in Princeton, 1959 November 10 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Letter from John Howard to CUWA Reporting on Talks in Washington with ACE-CIPA, ICA, IES, and State Department, 1959 November 24 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Docket for Princeton Meeting (CUWA) on December 29-30, 1959, 1959 December 29-30 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- CUWA Background Papers and Documents for March 14, 1960 Meeting (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Committe on the University and World Affiars -- Meeting in Washington, D.C. on March 14, 1960, 1960 March 14 (Box 8)
  - Meetings -- Committee on the University and World Affairs -- Meeting in Washington on July 18, 1960 -- Docket, 1960 July (Box 8)
  - U -- General Files, 1960 (Box 9)
  - W -- General Files, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
  - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
  - Meeting on Comparative and Overseas Education -- Gould House (L8-742), 1958 October 17-18 (Box 9)
  - Studies of Comparative Cultures and Religions, 1956-1958 (Box 9)
  - Conference on Comparative Economic Growth and Structure at Princeton University, 1958 June 27-28 (Box 9)
  - Conference on Higher Education for Distinguished Visiting Fulbright Scholars Sponsored by American University, CBARC and the State Department, 1961 June 14-18 (Box 9)
  - Council on Foreign Relations -- Philip E. Mosely, Director of Studies, 1955-1962 (Box 9)
  - Conference on Improving Resource Base in U.S. for Technical Assistance Overseas in Development Administration and Law, 1962 October 26-27 (Box 9)
  - Conference on Soviet and Chinese Communism Similarities and Differences -- Meeting at Lake Tahoe, 1965 June 13-17 (Box 9)
  - Cornell University -- General, 1957-1963 (Box 9)
  - Council on Foreign Relations -- Study Group on Human Factors in Economic Development -- Edwin J. Cohn, 1957-1958 (Box 9)
  - D -- General Files, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Dartmouth College -- Re: "A Proposal for an Overseas Service Program" -- John S. Dickey (L9-782), 1960 (Box 9)
  - E -- General Files, 1951-1965 (Box 9)
  - Education -- General, 1951-1964 (Box 9)
  - Education of American Children Overseas, 1956-1957 (Box 9)
  - Endowment Grants, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Europe -- Melvin J. Fox -- European Trip, 1963 May-June (Box 9)
  - Expiration Dates on ITR Grants -- Memoranda Re: Records, General, 1962-1964 (Box 9)
  - Exchange of Persons, 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - Exchange of Persons, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Exchange of Persons, 1952-1962 (Box 10)
  - Exchange of Persons -- Melvin Fox Files -- Speeches, Reports, etc., 1955-1966 (Box 10)
  - Exchange of Persons -- Task Force Paper, 1961-1965 (Box 10)
  - F -- General Files, 1951-1966 (Box 10)
  - Fellowship Program -- Announcements (see also press releases), 1952-1965 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Board of Overseas Training and Research (BOTR) -- Admission of Soviet and Slavic Area Training Scholarships, 1953 October 9-10 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Background Material on the International Training and Research (ITR) Foreign Area Training Fellowship Program, 1960-1961, 1961 March 16 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Foreign Area Fellowship Program (folder 1), 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Foreign Area Fellowship Program (folder 2), 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Foreign Area Fellowship Program -- Black Book, circa 1962-1963 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Princeton Conference on Fellowship Program, 1954 July 23-24 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Princeton Meeting Re: African Fellows, 1956 September 10-11 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Meeting of Former Fellows at Gould House, 1958 January 31-February 1 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Correspondence -- General File, 1952-1953 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Correspondence -- General File, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Correspondence -- General File, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Correspondence -- General File, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Correspondence -- General File, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Correspondence -- General File, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Program -- General File, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- Fellowship Program -- General File (see also SSRC grant PA62-88), 1962 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- International Training and Research (ITR), Travel and Study Awards Program (incl. INDEX) -- Internal Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- International Training and Research (ITR), Travel and Study Awards Program -- Internal Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- International Training and Research (ITR), Travel and Study Awards Program -- Internal Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- International Training and Research (ITR), Travel and Study Awards Program -- Instructions Re: Procedures, 1958-1966 (Box 10)
  - Fellowships -- International Training and Research (ITR), Travel and Study Awards Program -- Financial Reports from IIE, 1956-1959 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships -- International Training and Research (ITR), Travel and Study Awards Program -- Financial Reports from IIE, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships -- International Training and Research (ITR), Travel and Study Awards Program (incl. INDEX) -- Docket Items, Program Actions (PA56-14), 1964 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships -- Overseas Representatives -- General File -- Re: Fellowship Matters (see also individual country files), 1955 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships -- Burma Office -- Fellowship Matters -- Correspondence, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships -- India Office -- Fellowship Matters -- Correspondence, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships -- Indonesia Office -- Fellowship Matters -- Correspondence, 1954-1961 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships -- Near East Office -- Fellowship Matters -- Correspondence, 1961 (Box 11)